《反恐24小时》前情提要
Previously on 24.
在乔纳斯·霍奇斯被杀前
Before his death,
他说
Jonas Hodges told us
还有其他势力也参与了
That there were other parties involved with him
生化武器的研制
In the creation of this bioweapon.
联邦调查局已经拘押了托尼·阿尔梅达
The FBI has apprehended Tony almeida.
他是这次阴谋的关键人物
He is a key figure in this plot,
乔纳斯·霍奇斯是在调查局总部外被杀的
Jonas Hodges was killed outside FBI headquarters.
可能跟泰勒小姐有关
Ms. Taylor Might be involved.
奥利维亚的确有很多手段
Olivia is capable of many things,
但我不相信她会去杀人
But I can't believe committing murder is one of them.
我需要你打开数字录音系统
I need you to access the digital recording system.
看是否有他们的对话录音
To see if their conversation was recorded.
我无法忍受的是那个恶棍逍遥法外
What I can't live with is that monster getting away with this.
我手下的人跟你女儿在一起
My operatives are with your daughter.
实际上  我现在就看着她呢
In fact, I'm looking at her right now.
你得帮助托尼·阿尔梅达脱身
You will help Tony Almeida escape
不然我的人会杀了你女儿
Or my people will murder your daughter.
不许动
Don't move.
杰克  为什么这样做
Jack, why?
托尼的同伙
The people that are working with Tony
派了人监视金
Have operatives with Kim right now.
如果我不把他弄出去  他们说会杀了她
They threatened to kill her if I don't break him out.
那些监视你的人
People who are watching you,
是找到你父亲的唯一线索
They're our only lead to finding your father
那个笔记本上有用来监视我的摄像头
That laptop has the camera they were using to track me.
也许可以反向追踪到抓我父亲的人
We may be able to back trace to the people that have my father.
你的人可以按原计划
Your people are gonna be able to launch the biological attacks
发动生化袭击
Just as they originally planned.
我们还有杰克
We have Jack.
病原体就在他的身体里
The pathogen's in his organs.
我们可以从他身体里提取我们想要的东西
We'll be able to harvest everything we need from his body.
托尼相信我们做的事
Tony believes in what we're doing.
你是说我得跟他见面吗
Are you suggesting I meet with him?
我会好好看看阿尔梅达
I'll look Almeida in the eye,
如果有任何地方让我不高兴
And if, for any reason, I don't like what I see,
他就别想活着离开
I can't let him walk out of that meeting alive.
他还有多少时间
How much longer does he have?
几个小时左右
A couple of hours, give or take.
人死亡后病原体能存活两小时
The pathogen could survive up to two hours after death,
实际上  杀死病原体的唯一方法
In fact, the only sure way to destroy it
是将其暴露在在500摄氏温度的高温里
Is by exposure to extreme temperatures above 500-degrees celsius.
让他起来走了
Get him ready to move.
以下情节发生在凌晨7点至8点间
The following takes place between 7 a.m. and 8 a.m.
如果需要找些人来帮你  就告诉我
Tell me if you need more people on this and I will get them for you.
我们不需要人  我们需要的是运气
We don't need people. we need to get lucky.
笔记本里的发送器节点是多个中继加密的
The transmitter node on the laptop is encrypted with multiple relays.
能不能找到发送的接收源
Can you source the transmission or not?
我正想办法
I'm trying to come up with a work-around.
想到马上告诉我
Call me as soon as you have something.
还是找不到接收源吗
They still can't source the transmission?
他们正努力
They're working on it.
克罗伊和詹尼斯正竭尽所能
Chloe and Janis are doing everything that they can.
没有其他的线索或者方法找到我爸爸了吗
Is there no other lead, no other way to find my father?
金  这已经是很有用的线索了
This is a good lead, kim.
我们找到这线索多亏了你
The only reason we have it is 'cause of you.
但我爸爸却快死了
Yeah, except my father's dying.
我们不知道他还剩多少时间
And we don't know how much time he has left.
请进
Come in.
你还在这里干什么
What are you still doing here?
继续我们未完的对话
Just finishing up the conversation we started.
亚伦
Aaron,
我已经叫你把伊桑送出去了
I told you to escort ethan to the gate.
现在把他带出我的办公室  带出白宫
Now take him out of my office and off the white house grounds.
女士  我不能那样做
No, ma'am, I am not gonna do that.
我叫保安来了
I'm calling security.
要我挖出诺亚·丹尼尔斯的丑闻是一回事
Having me dig up dirt on Noah Daniels is one thing.
但这次就完全不同了
This is a whole different animal.
这个我明白  马丁
I'm aware of that, Martin.
替我办成此事  我要你好好收拾这恶贼
I want this to happen. I want this person taken care of.
是乔纳斯·霍格斯
It's Jonas Hodges.
你从我那里搜走的数字存储片是空白的
The digital card you confiscated from me was blank.
我把真的给皮尔斯探员了
I gave the real one to agent Pierce.
亚伦  你知道这事多久了
How long have you known, Aaron?
女士  我有怀疑  但我本希望我错了
I had my suspicions, ma'am, but I was hoping I was wrong.
我出去等  先生
I'll wait outside, sir.
伊桑  这并不是事实的全部
Ethan, this doesn't tell the whole story.
对我来说已经够清楚了
Sounds pretty clear to me.
霍奇斯死了  是因为你
Hodges is dead, you're responsible.
我知道  可我本想阻止这事发生的
I know, but I tried to stop it from happening.
省省吧  奥利维亚
Oh, save it, Olivia!
你这次可不能耍耍嘴皮子就想没事
You can't talk your way out of this situation, not this time.
好吧  伊桑
All right, Ethan...
你赢了
You win.
我会辞职
I'll resign.
编个借口
Come up with some excuse.
你可以复职了
You could have your job again.
什么事都
Everything will go...
我不是回来抢工作的
This isn't about getting my job back!
是为了真相
It's about the truth!
真相会危及到我妈妈的政权
The truth could destroy my mother's administration.
这事公开的结果
I am fully aware of the implications
我比谁都清楚
If this goes public.
不用你来告诉我
You don't have to spell them out for me.
那你想干嘛
Then what do you want?
留给总统去决定
For the president to take the next step.
继续追究还是保持缄默
Whether she decides to prosecute this or bury it,
这是她的决定
That's her call.
她应该知道真相
But she needs to know the truth.
你自己去跟她讲吧
I'll let you tell her yourself.
真不敢相信你会这样做
I can't believe you're doing this.
你背叛了你所有的信仰
You're betraying everything that you've ever worked for.
我知道这个国家让你失望了
I know you think this country failed you,
我也不在乎你现在的信仰变成了什么样
And I don't care what kind of ideology you believe in now.
这绝不值得你去做
This is no way to fight for it.
你在做的一切都是错的
What you're doing is wrong.
这么做是错的  你知道的
This is wrong, and you know it!
托尼  看着我
Damn it, Tony, look at me!
我求你
Please...
看在我们曾经私交甚笃的面子上
As someone who was once your friend...
让我平静的死去吧
Let me die in peace.
不要让他们用我杀无辜的人了
Don't let them use me to kill innocent people.
我根本没想让他们
I have no intention of letting them use you
在你身体里提取病原体  杰克
As a pathogen, Jack.
我没真么想过
I never did.
我听见你说的了
I overheard you. this was your idea.
你卖给他们的
You sold it to them.
只是做戏而已
It was just a play.
做戏
A play?
是引诱那个幕后主使过来
To get the man who's coming here right now.
花了我三年找到他
Took me three years to find him.
又用了一年
Took me another year
能和他面对面
To get him to meet me face-to-face.
我杀了乔纳斯·霍奇斯
I had to prove myself to him
向他证明我的能力
By taking down Jonas Hodges.
我用这个向他阐明我对他的信仰深信不疑
I had to convince him that I was a true believer in his cause.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
他叫阿兰·威尔森
His name is Alan Wilson.
是查尔斯·罗根的的幕后主使
He was the man behind Charles Logan.
就是他下令杀了大卫·普拉莫
He's the one who ordered the hit on david palmer,
他杀了蜜雪儿掩盖这一切
And he had michelle killed to cover his tracks.
这个男人杀了我的爱妻
This is the man who murdered my wife, Jack.
你今天做的这一切都是为了复私仇
Everything that you've done today is for personal revenge?
是为了正义
It's about justice.
正义  你杀了无辜的人  托尼
Justice. you killed innocent people, Tony!
要不是我这么做
Ten times as many people would have died if it hadn't
十倍于今天的人会死
Been for me. the deeper I dug
我对蜜雪儿的死调查的越深
To find the person responsible for michelle's death,
遇到很多像乔纳斯·霍奇斯一样的人
The more I kept running into men like Jonas Hodges.
那些疯狂的想法是他们的  不是我的
They're the ones with the crazy ideology, Jack, not me.
我是要把他们一个个击垮
I'm the one who had a plan to bring them down.
我让比尔和克洛伊
I'd enlisted bill and chloe to help me
帮我把组织的每个环节都挖出来
Track all the elements of this group.
当我找到真相的时候
And when I finally got what I wanted,
就会把这一切揭开   击垮他们
They would turn 'em in and shut 'em down.
你毁了这一切
But you screwed
对不对  杰克
That all up, didn't you, Jack?
我是拯救生命的英雄  不是你
You see, I'm the one who saved lives today, Jack, not you.
是我拿回了CIP模块
I'm the one who helped you recover the cip device,
是我警告你关白宫的袭击
I'm the one who warned you about the white house attacks,
是我阻止了乔纳斯·霍奇斯
I'm the one who stopped Jonas Hodges
发射飞弹
From launching those missiles!
你愿意怎么自我安慰就自便吧
You tell yourself whatever you want.
你在华盛顿中央地铁站
You launched a biological attack
发动生化袭击
On washington center station,
要不是我们及时赶到
And if we hadn't gotten there in time,
上千无辜平民就死在你手里了
Thousands of innocent people would have been killed!
我只是做了我必须做的引来威尔森
I did what I had to do to get Alan Wilson there.
现在我要杀了他
And now he's gonna die.
你杀了他  就没人知道
You kill him, and no one will ever know the full extent
整个阴谋了
Of this conspiracy.
我不会杀他的  杰克
I'm not gonna kill him, jack...
是你
You are.
托尼  妈的
Damn you, tony. damn you.
对不起这样对你
I'm sorry that it has to be you,
因为他们不会让我在他
But the truth is, they wouldn't let me
50尺之内的
Within 50 feet of the guy.
他是来要你的
You're the one he's coming for.
你不是在缅怀蜜雪儿
You're not honoring michelle's life.
你利用了她的死
You are reveling in her death, and she would
而她会因此看不起你
Despise you for this.
装置已装备完毕
Device armed.
安全了
We're clear.
威尔森什么时候到
When's wilson coming?
快到了
Soon.
他想看鲍尔的病历
He wants to see bauer's medical record.
威尔森不认识我们
Wilson doesn't know about us.
最好保持原样  至少现在保持这样
And it's best to keep it that way, at least for now.
好
Sure.
我明白
I understand.
他来了
He's here.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
Yeah.
走
Let's go.
双手放在脑后
Put your hands behind your head.
全部安全  先生
We're all clear, sir.
别向前走了
That's far enough for you.
你好
Hello,
我是卡拉
Cara.
这位是托尼·阿尔梅达
This is Tony Almeida.
我期盼这天已经很久了  先生
I've been looking forward to this, sir.
我知道
Yes, I know.
鲍尔在哪里
Where's Bauer?
就在里面
Right inside.
第二个门进去右转
Second door on the right.
带上这个
Need this.
卡拉认为该提拔你
So Cara thinks you should be playing a larger role
在我们组织当个领导
In our organization.
你功不可没
You've been an asset.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
但我还能为组织贡献更多
But I believe there's a lot more I can bring to the table.
可事先
But first,
我得先看看鲍尔的病理学报告
I want to see Bauer's pathology report.
我带来了
I have it right here.
我们是联邦调查局
This is the FBI!
你们被包围了
You're surrounded!
放下武器
Lay down your weapons!
快  自由开火
Come on. Fire at will!
我重复一遍  放下武器
I repeat, lay down your weapons!
托尼
Tony!
放我们下去
Set us down.
带我去那辆绿色货车  快
I need you to get me to that green van! Go!
杰克
Jack.
离我远点  我被绑上了C4炸药
Stay away from me; i'm wired with C4.
引爆器在托尼手里
Tony's got the detonator.
走开
Stay away!
等等  我懂这种触发原理
Wait, I know this trigger mechanism.
我可以拆卸炸药
I can disarm it.
金在哪里
Where's Kim?
她很安全
She's safe.
我们靠她才找到了你
She's the reason we were able to find you.
托尼一直在上演无间道
Tony's been playing both sides all along.
你赶快去制止他
You need to stop him.
他想去杀幕后黑手
He's trying to kill the man who's behind this conspiracy.
这人名叫艾伦·威尔森
His name is Alan Wilson.
是他杀死了托尼的妻子米歇尔
He was responsible for killing Tony's wife Michelle.
所以他精心策划了这次行动
That's why he's doing this.
如果你想永远组织这场灾难
You want to end this for good,
就得马上阻止托尼杀害他
You need to stop Tony from killing him.
否则就会失去机会  将其他成员一网打尽
Otherwise, you're gonna lose any chance of exposing the others.
好了  安全了
Okay, you're clear.
快走
Let's go.
这里是伍德塞的工业中心
Woodside industrial complex.
我们正在通往警戒线的东南区域
We're at the southeast quadrant on our way to the perimeter.
找到突围口后联系我
Call me when you have an exfiltration point.
怎么会这样
How did this happen?
他们怎么会追踪到我们
How did they track us?
不清楚
I don't know.
托尼
Tony!
谢天谢地你安然无恙
Thank god you're okay.
突围小队快到了
The extraction team will be here soon,
可我们得继续赶路
But we got to move.
我花了好长时间才找到你
It took me a long time to find you.
我抽丝剥茧  才发现你是幕后主使
To peel back all the layers of people you hide behind.
可我依然静观其变
But I stayed patient.
因为你派人杀害她那天起
Because ever since the day you had her killed,
唯一让我活下去的动力
The only thing that kept me alive
就是等待此时此刻的到来
Was this moment right here.
你的语气好像在说你是某种悲剧的受害者
Mm, you sound like you were involved in
但和我毫不相干
Some kind of a tragedy, but I had nothing to do with it.
你看  我和米歇尔
See, Michelle and me
患难与共
Had gotten out of all this.
我们最终走到了一起
We made it out together.
并准备开始过崭新的生活
And we were gonna start a whole new life.
直到你出现
Until you came along
就在那一瞬间
And took it all away
夺走了一切幸福美好
In a split second.
你不只谋杀了我老婆
It wasn't just my wife you murdered.
她正怀着我儿子
She was carrying my son.
你杀了我儿子
You killed my son!
我儿子
My son!
现在
And now
我要杀了你丫的
I'm gonna kill you.
托尼  不许动
Tony, don't move.
Tony, don't move!
带他出去
Get him out of here.
不
no!
杰克  这些人以为他们能夺走我们的一切
These people think they can take everything away from us, Jack!
必须有人阻止他们
Somebody had to stop them!
看你做了什么
And what'd you do, huh?!
你逃开了
You ran away!
没错  杰克  你逃开了
That's right, you ran away, Jack!
你现在跟他们是一路货色了
You're one of them now!
恭喜你
Congratulations!
泰莉会怎么想呢
How would Teri feel about that,
啊  杰克  啊
huh, Jack?! huh?!
你没种了啊
You lost your nerve!
杰克  你是个懦夫
You're a coward, Jack!
因为你  今天死了很多人
A lot od people died today because of you.
包括我身边的人
Including someone close to me.
你将面临叛国罪以及
You will be charged with treason and conspiracy to launch
阴谋发动恐怖袭击罪的起诉
Terrorist attacks against this country.
唯有跟我们合作
The only way that I see you
你才能够避免被判死刑
Avoiding the death penalty is by cooperating.
告诉我们还有谁参与了这个阴谋
Tell me who else is involved in this conspiracy,
我敢保证陪审团会
And I will make sure that your cooperation
考虑到你的合作态度从轻发落
Is taken into account by the grand jury.
我都不明白你说的是什么  谈何合作呢
How can I cooperate if I have no idea what you're talking about?
威尔森  不要垂死挣扎了
It's not gonna work, Wilson.
无论你认为我
Whatever this conspiracy is
参与了何种阴谋  我向你保证
That you think that I'm a part of, I guarantee
你不会找到任何有关我的物证
You won't find a shred of material evidence connecting me to it.
法律上说  我是无辜的
In the eyes of the law, I'm an innocent man.
你个畜生
You son of a bitch!
还有什么要说的话
Anything else you need to say,
可以跟我的律师说
You can say to my attorneys.
女士
Ma'am.
他们准备好送鲍尔去医院了
They're almost ready to take Bauer to the hospital.
你让我们通知你的
You wanted a heads up.
我将给你注射二氢吗啡酮
I'm giving you hydromorphone
让你在途中舒服一点
To make the ride to the hospital easier.
它会让你有些瞌睡
It'll make you a little sleepy,
-可以止痛  -不  暂时不用
- But it will break the pain cycle.  - No, not yet.
求你了
Please.
杰克
Jack.
让我们单独待会儿
Could you give us a moment?
麦斯医生要求你去医院
Dr. Macer wants you at the hospital.
没关系  让她等会儿
It's all right, she can wait.
谢谢
Thank you.
发生什么事
What happened?
他推得一干二净
He's denying everything.
他说我们无证据指控他
Claims that we don't have a case against him.
是这样吗
Is he right?
也许吧
Maybe.
也就是说他没有理由说出
Which means he has absolutely no reason
他同党的名字
To tell us who else is involved in this with him.
但我可以让他开口
But I can make him talk.
如果不找到这些人
If we don't find these people,
总有一天他们还会发动袭击
One day they will launch another attack,
我不知道自己怎么能忍受
And I don't see how I can live with myself
明知自己可以阻止袭击的发生
Knowing that there was something I could have done to stop it.
我不知道该做什么
I don't know what to do.
我不能告诉你该怎么做
I can't tell you what to do.
这一生我都在纠缠于这种事
I've been wrestling with this one my whole life.
如果我眼看着汽车上有15名人质
I-I see 15 people held hostage on a bus,
其他的一切我都不管了
And everything else goes out the window.
为了救他们我愿意做任何事  我是说
And I will do whatever it takes to save them, and I mean
不择手段
Whatever it takes.
我想大概是我以为
I guess maybe I thought...
如果救了他们
If I save them...
我也救了自己
I'd save myself.
今天做的事情你后悔吗
Do you regret anything that you did today?
不
No.
还是那句话  我是不是调查局的人
Then again, I don't work for the FBI.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你宣誓过
You took an oath.
你承诺要效忠法律
You made a promise to uphold the law.
当你越过那条底线的时候
When you cross that line,
一步错步步错
It always starts off with a small step.
在你觉察到之前  你一个劲地跑
Before you know it, you're running as fast as you can
却是南辕北辙
In the wrong direction.
只是为了证明你的初衷
Just to justify what you started in the first place.
这些法律是一些
These laws were written
比你我都聪明多的人编写的
By much smarter men than me.
最后我知道这些法条
And in the end, I know that these laws
一定得比公交上的15条人命重要
Have to be more important than the 15 people on the bus.
在我心底
I know that's right.
我知道那是对的
In my mind,
I know that's right.
我只是认为我的心无法承受这些
I just don't think my heart could ever have lived with it.
我想我能给你的唯一建议就是
I guess the only advice I can give you is...
去做那些你能承受的选择
Try to make choices that you can live with.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
那就什么都别说
Don't say anything at all.
鲍尔先生  我们该走了
Mr. Bauer, we really need to go.
亨利
Henry!
你下床来干什么
What are you doing out of bed?
发生了什么事
What's going on?
奥利维亚说你来了才肯说
Olivia wouldn't say until you got here.
当我说出口时你们会明白
You'll understand when I tell you.
开口一次都足够艰难
It's gonna be hard enough to say once.
说吧  利维
I'm listening, Livy.
这是怎么了
What's this about?
乔纳斯·霍奇斯
Jonas Hodges.
他是因为我才死的
He's dead because of me.
利维
Oh, Livy,
别告诉我
Don't tell me you were the one
是你把消息泄露出去的
Who leaked the information.
比那更糟
It's worse than that.
奥利维亚
Olivia...
跟我们说
Talk to us.
他谋杀了罗杰
He killed Roger.
霍奇斯谋杀了我弟弟
Hodges killed my brother.
但你却同意让他加入证人保护计划
And then you agreed to put him into witness protection.
一想到他会逃脱惩罚
And the thought of him getting away
我就忍受不了
Was too much for me.
所以我打电话给马丁·柯里尔
So I called Martin Collier.
他曾今
He had once...
跟我说过他认识一些人可以做这类事
Told me he knew someone who could do this kind of thing.
你是说  柯里尔雇人
You're saying... Collier hired someone
谋杀了乔纳斯·霍奇斯
To kill Jonas Hodges?
不
No.
是我雇的
I did.
我叫停过
I tried calling it off,
但是一切都太晚了  事情发生得太快
But it was too late, and everything was happening so fast.
奥利维亚
Olivia...
还有谁知道这些
Who else knows about this?
伊桑
Ethan.
他有一份录音
He has a recording
记录了我和马丁的谈话
Of my conversation with Martin.
他同意不交给司法部长
He's agreed not to turn it over to the attorney general.
他还说会尊重您的决定  证据任由您处置
He says he'll respect whatever you decide to do with the evidence.
妈  说些话吧
Mom, say something.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do this?!
奥利维亚
Olivia!
你怎么能这么做如此愚蠢之事
How could you do something so stupid?
对不起  我发誓  我叫停过
I'm sorry-- I tried to call it off, I swear!
那不重要  亲爱的  事已至此
It doesn't matter, darling, it happened!
看在老天的份上
For god's sake,
艾莉森  别再朝她吼叫了
Allison, stop yelling at her.
霍奇斯谋杀了我们的儿子
Hodges killed our son.
我知道是他干的
I know what he did.
所以如果有人该死  一定是他
Then you know if anyone deserves to die, it's him.
你现在该考虑的
All you should be thinking about now
就是如何保护我们的女儿
Is how to protect our daughter.
保护她
Protect her?
怎么保护
How?
销毁证据
Destroy that recording.
然后掩饰一桩谋杀案吗
And cover up a murder?
亨利  我不能无视法律啊
Henry, I can't just disregard the law!
艾莉森  别假装神圣了
Allison, spare me your sanctimony.
你是奥利维亚的母亲
You're Olivia's mother.
我也是美国的总统
I'm also the president of the United States.
可我们家已经为此付出了沉重的代价
And our family's already paid a steep enough price for that.
你在说什么啊  亨利
What are you saying, Henry?
你知道我在说什么
You know exactly what I'm saying.
你的工作葬送了我们的儿子
Your job cost our son his life.
这么说太残忍了
That is a cruel thing to say.
我无法阻止罗杰遇害
I couldn't have done anything to prevent Roger's death.
但你能做些事来阻止这件事
But you can do something about this.
看在老天的份上  艾莉森
For god's sakes, Allison...
我们已经失去了一个孩子
We've already lost one child.
对不起打扰  总统阁下
I'm sorry to interrupt, madam president,
但是调查局有些消息过来
But there's some news from the bureau
您需要听一下
You need to hear.
是好消息
Uh, good news.
我一会过去  蒂姆
I'll be down in a moment, Tim.
是的  阁下
Yes, ma'am.
去吧  艾莉森
Go, Allison.
可你要答应我
But so help me...
毁掉那段录音
Destroy that recording...
来保护这个家里仅剩的成员
And save what's left of this family.
去吧
Go.
爸  我都做了些什么
Dad, what did I do?
我们会妥善处理
We're going to figure this out.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们会妥善处理
We'll figure it out.
他是个重要嫌犯
He's a high-value suspect--
在我赶去之前  确保封锁所有出口
Make sure you restrict access until I get there.
沃克探员正在带他返回
Agent Walker's bringing him back now.
-他们什么时候到  -10分钟之内
- What's their ETA? - About ten minutes.
我20分钟之内到
I'll be there in 20--
在那之前把威尔森的移交文件处理好
Have Wilson's transfer papers in order by then.
克罗伊  打扰一下
Excuse me, Chloe?
我要去处理威尔森的移交文件
I've got to work on Wilson's transfer papers,
所以我们晚些时候再汇报情况
So we're gonna have to schedule debriefing for later.
我可以晚点再来  明天也行
I can come back later, or tomorrow.
你住在城里吗
You staying in town?
我想在这里帮杰克
I want to be here for Jack.
我要谢谢你  你今天给了我很大帮助
I'd like to thank you for all the help you gave me today.
是的  很有趣
Yeah, it was... interesting.
考虑到你得和别人共事
Given what you have to work with,
你做的很不错
You're doing a pretty good job.
我把这句话当做表扬了  谢谢
I'll take that as a compliment. Thank you.
很好  其实我就是那个意思
Good. That's what it was meant to be.
因为病原体已经武器化了
Because the pathogen was weaponized,
你的病已经到了晚期
The disease is at an advanced stage.
鲍尔先生  我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Mr. Bauer.
我所能做的只有给你注射吗啡
All I can do is administer morphine,
那会引起昏迷  但你不会感觉疼痛
Which will induce a coma, but you won't feel any pain.
不用吗啡  不用  拜托
No morphine. Not yet, please.
打扰一下  梅瑟尔医生  有人来看鲍尔先生
Excuse me, Dr. Macer. Mr. Bauer has a visitor.
没事
Yeah, it's all right.
他现在要见你
He'll see you now.
我就在外面
I'll be outside.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
我很意外接到你的电话
I was surprised to get your call.
我快死了
I'm dying.
我知道
I know.
我犯了太多错误
I made so many mistakes.
而且我总以为  我早晚会有时间
And I always thought that I would have the time
亡羊补牢
To correct them.
你有时间的
You have the time.
现在就可以
Right now.
你不知道我做过什么
You don't know what I've done.
我们生活在复杂的世界里  鲍尔先生
We live in complex times, Mr. Bauer.
是非黑白没有明确的界限
Nothing is black and white.
可我知道
But I do know this.
我看见我面前的这位男子
I see before me a man
他既有缺点
With all his flaws
也有美德
And all his goodness.
只是一个人
Simply a man.
让我们一起宽恕我们自己吧
Let us both forgive ourselves
宽恕我们犯下的所有过错
For all the wrongs that we have done.
谢谢
Thank you.
是时候了
It's time.
奥利维亚  过来坐
Olivia, come and sit down.
不  我不行
No, I can't.
我从没有想到  我的工作会
I never imagined that this job would...
会给你们两带来如此沉重的负担
Would be so hard on both of you.
我不知道这个家要付出怎样的代价
I had no idea of the price this family would pay.
对此  我很抱歉
And for that, I am so sorry.
但是我宣誓过  我有责任
But I have a sworn duty
严格执法
To enforce the constitution.
如果不能履行誓言  那将是最不堪的虚伪
And failing to honor that oath...would be the worst kind of hypocrisy.
奥利维亚  我爱你胜过世间万物
Olivia, I love you more than anything in this world
我会竭尽所能帮你渡过难关
and I will do everything I can to help you through this...
但作为总统  我必须大义灭亲
but as president,this is what I have to do...
尽管这将会让我心碎欲绝
no matter how much it breaks my heart.
皮尔斯探员会把你送交联邦政府羁押
Agent Pierce will remand youto federal custody.
女士  我护送您去司法部
Ma'am, I'm escorting you to the Justice Department...
在正式的指控提出之前
where you'll be held until formal charges...
您将待在那里
have been issued.
对不起  亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
亨利
Henry.
艾莉森
Allison.
-要是你现在不想谈   -不
- if you'd like to talk later...  - No.
虽然我很想息事宁人
As much as I wanted to cover this up,
我  我不能那么做
I... I couldn't.
你不必解释  总统阁下
You don't have to explain yourself to me, madam president.
我完全理解
I understand completely.
亨利不理解
Henry doesn't.
他会想通的
He'll come around.
迟早
in time.
他不会的  伊桑
I don't think he will, Ethan.
真的
I really don't.
我失去了我的家庭
I've lost my family.
失去了所有人
I've lost everyone.
不是所有人
Not everyone.
那你愿意收回辞职信了吗
Then you'll take back your letter of resignation?
如果你希望的话
If you want me to.
我希望
I do.
我需要你的帮助  伊桑
I need your help, Ethan,
现在就需要
and I need it now.
调查局抓到一个人
The FBI has taken a man into custody.
名字是艾伦·威尔森
His name is Alan Wilson.
伍兹已经去提审威尔森了
Woods is on his way to pick up Wilson,
你需要签发移交文件
And you need to sign the transfer documents.
怎么了
What's wrong?
出什么事了
What's going on?
出去下  詹尼丝
Get out of here, Janis.
-什么  -我说了出去
- Excuse me? - I said get out of here.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
出去
Get out.
不  绝对不
No. Absolutely not.
威尔森被移交前我不会走的
I'm staying right here until Wilson is transferred.
很好
Fine.
你在干什么
What are you...?
-你在干什么  -把手放在头上
- What are you doing? - Put your hands over your head.
我让你把手放在头上  詹尼丝
I said do it now, Janis!
把你的手拷在柱子上
Secure your hands to that pole.
-快  -好的好的
- Now! - Okay, okay, okay.
冷静下来  行吗  冷静
Just-just alm down, all right? Just...
蕾妮  别这么做
Renee, please don't do this.
别这么做
Please don't do this.
你做了分内事
You've done your job.
你逮捕了他
You arrested him.
剩下的让检察院来管吧
Let the courts take it from here.
你现在收手 还为时不晚
Stop this now... Before it's too late.
别自毁前程
Don't throw away your career.
你这么做简直疯了
This is absolutely insane.
拉里肯定不想你这样
Larry would not have wanted this.
不要让他蒙羞
Don't dishonor his death like this.
爸爸
Daddy.
我来晚了
I'm too late.
不  金  他还活着
No, he's still alive, Kim.
我们让他昏迷
We induced a coma to help
缓解愈加严重的症状带给他的痛苦
Ease him through the harsher symptoms.
我叫高哈
My name is Gohar.
是他的朋友
I'm a friend.
朋友
A friend?
他昏迷前几分钟我和他谈过
We spent the last few minutes talking
我可以告诉你  他已经接受了事实
And I can tell you he's accepted what is happening.
他是接受了
Maybe he has.
但我还没有
But I haven't.
你告诉我的那个干细胞疗法
The stem cell treatment that you told me about.
现在还能做吗
Can we still do it?
我告诉过你  这种方法还处于实验阶段
As I told you, it's experimental
而且成功率很低
And the odds of success are very low.
你只要告诉我还来不来得及
Just tell me if it's too late to try.
来得及
No.
那我要求这么做
Then I want to do it.
但是  风险
The risks--
我知道有风险
I understand the risks.
我也知道我的父亲不想我尝试救他
And I know my father didn't want me to take that chance,
但现在是我自己的选择
But it's my choice now
我意已决
And I made up my mind.
我是桑尼·梅瑟尔
This is Sunny Macer.
我现在急需一套手术设备
I need immediate access to a surgical suite.
让罗森医生马上打给我
Have Dr. Rosen call me right away.
对不起  爸爸
I'm sorry, daddy.
但我不想让你离我而去
But I'm not ready to let you go.